# LAURA WHALEN

# **Data Analytics Student**

Eager, knowledge-hungry Data Analytics student, keen to meet challenges, quickly understands new concepts and programs, and ready to adapt and progress in a growing and progressing field. Extensive experience with client service and thrives in establishing and maintaining strong respectful relationships with clients and colleagues.



Halifax, NS



902-877-4388



whalenmlaura@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/whalenmlaura



github.com/whalenmlaura



whalenmlaura.com

#### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

#### Diploma, IT Data Analytics | Nova Scotia Community College

SEPT 2018 - JUNE 2020

- Fundamentals of logic and programming with Python and Java using Visual Studio Code and Eclipse.
- Writing SQL queries in various database management systems (Microsoft SQL Server, SQLite, MariaDB).
- Knowledge of key concepts and methodologies used by business analysts, understanding of how gathered information is used to support strategic and tactical decision-making in business.
- Basics of statistical learning using R in RStudio.

## Emergency First Aid with CPR "C"/AED | Life Saving Society of Nova Scotia

JUNE 2016 - JUNE 2019

#### Bachelor of Arts, Criminology minor Sociology, Psychology | Saint Mary's University

SEPT 2010 - MAY 2014

- Dean's List (2013/2014)

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Computer Assisted Telephone Interviewer | Statistics Canada**

JUNE 2018 - PRESENT

- Conduct data gathering activities while ensuring data collection materials and documents are kept physically secure at all times, and that confidentiality is maintained.
- Gather institutional, economic, and social survey information while developing and maintaining a productive and harmonious relationship with the survey respondent.

#### **Evaluation Assessment Assistant | Strongest Families Institute**

JAN 2018 – AUG 2018

- Scheduled and administered the Brief Child and Family Phone Interview (BCFPI) to both adults and youth to ensure the client met requirements for a program within the Strongest Families Institute.
- Handled sensitive topics about mental health in a professional and empathetic manner to establish a meaningful therapeutic alliance.

#### **Information Services Clerk | McInnes Cooper**

SEPT 2014 - DEC 2017

- Conducted and prepared conflict of interest reports for more than 180 lawyers within the firm to avoid legal and business conflicts.
- Coordinated multiple daily tasks and prioritized based on urgency and importance to ensure lawyers and paraprofessionals
   had adequate time to prepare legal documents and to prepare for client meetings and court.
- Performed research and analysis to ensure data integrity for the benefit of the firm, and monitored and tracked daily workflow to update statistics in order to assist in the establishment of evidence-based procedure changes and updates.

#### Student Assistant – Patrick Power Library | Saint Mary's University

SEPT 2011 - APR 2014

- Processed books for students, faculty, and other patrons to ensure regulated flow and accessibility of library materials.
- Inputted and updated new patrons and students into the library's database using ALEPH software to ensure accuracy of all registrant's records.
- Shelved library materials using the Library of Congress Classification System to ensure books and journals were in the correct spot to be easily accessed by patrons.

# Teaching Assistant – Department of Sociology & Criminology | Saint Mary's University

SEPT 2013 - DEC 2013

- Marked *Quantitative Research Methods*, and *Social Inequality and Justice* courses for over 60 undergraduate students by following an answer key and using academic judgment and experience.
- Input student grades into Excel spreadsheets to increase efficiency and accessibility of student grade history.
- Collaborated and conducted regular follow-up sessions with professors to ensure all assignments, midterms, and projects were submitted and recorded in an productive manner.

#### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

## **Public Speaking Event | Nova Scotia Community College**

**DEC 2018** 

Participated in the NSCC Institute of Technology Campus public speaking event. Presented a speech on procrastination tips
for students while demonstrating clear articulation, using a good pace, tone, and volume, controlled presentation anxiety,
and a well-researched and practiced speech.

#### Volunteer Player / Non-Team Member Player | Nova Scotia Wheelchair Basketball

NOV 2017 - PRESENT

- Participate in skill developing drills and scrimmages to ensure the members of the team get adequate practice to prepare for games and tournaments.

#### Restorative Justice Co-Facilitator / Community Rep | Community Justice Society

SEPT 2015 - PRESENT

- Facilitate and guide restorative justice sessions by summarizing each participant's perspective, and keeping the conversation balanced.
- Communicate effectively, and calmly deal with conflicts or stressful interactions by fostering a mutual understanding and respect between participants.
- Assist in the development of a mutual agreement/legal contract by suggesting programs, number of community service hours, restitution amount, and various other terms, that is achievable and realistic for the client.

## **Volunteer Tutor | Pathways to Education**

JAN 2014 - JUNE 2014

- Tutored youth from grade 9-12 in various subjects, using different teaching techniques by adapting to students' various learning abilities and styles.
- Educated, guided, and assisted youth to understand school material, make a meaningful connection with school, and reduce at-risk behavior.

# **Distinctions and Certificates**

#### **Honourable Mention | Challenge Nova Scotia**

**NOV 2018** 

- Competed and recognized for a video submission of a solution to the question, "what can we do to ensure that innovators and entrepreneurs have the opportunities, drive and supports needed to commercialize ideas, build great companies and create jobs for Nova Scotians?"